Kelly Savietta

Senior Software Engineer

Full stack developer with 4+ years of production experience and demonstrated expertise managing projects in deadline-oriented environments. Highly adept at conveying complex technical information to a variety of professional and lay audiences in a clear and understandable manner.

Experience

2017-12 present

Senior Software Engineer

3Play Media (Transcription & Captioning) - Boston, MA

- Technical lead for design and implementation of 3Play Media's assisted transcription and audio description editing tools, an essential component of 3Play Media's product pipeline.
- Provides regular code review to ensure robust architectural design and evaluate security and performance concerns
- Technical consulting for large company initiatives and team resource allocation according to Agile methodologies
- Invested in direct mentorship of junior developers through pair programming, code review, and providing timely constructive feedback

2014-03 -2017-12

Software Engineer

3Play Media (Transcription & Captioning) - Boston, MA

- Responsible for all stages of the feature release cycle: from initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and feature maintenance. Built features to fulfill the needs of the operations, support, and product teams.
- Assisted in the planning, development and maintenance of the newest release of 3Play Media's API
- Built and maintains cloud storage delivery integrations (API integrations with Dropbox, Box, Google Drive, Aspera and YouTube)
- Built and maintains 3Play Media's translation partner integrations (DotSub, Gengo)
- Built automated application and on-boarding system to scale our transcription team as required

2013-11 -

Apprentice Full Stack Developer

2014-02

Launch Academy - Boston, MA

- A 3-month intensive web development bootcamp that teaches RoR/Javascript with a strong emphasis on practical programming skills, TDD and Agile practices.
- Built a Social Purchase Planning app that connects friends, housemates and significant others.

2012-12 -

Human Resources Coordinator

2013-10

Raytheon BBN Technologies - Cambridge, MA

Education

2008-09 -

Oberlin College

2012-05

Bachelor of Arts | Majors: Philosophy & Psychology

Courses and Volunteer

2015-01

Introduction to Computer Science (CSCI E-50) - Harvard Extension School

2014-01

Teaching Assistant @ Railsbridge Boston

Interests

Playing board games, biking, experimenting with cocktail recipes

Personal Info

Address

Madison, WI

Website

ksavietta.com

Github

github.com/ksavietta

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ksavietta

Technologies

Rails

Angular

jQuery

Relational Databases

NoSQL (MongoDB)

Redis & Resque

AWS (S3, Cloudfront)

Languages

Ruby

••••

Javascript & Typescript

•••••

SQL

HTML & HAML

CSS/SASS/SCSS

Python